A Guide to the Rose Greely Architectural Drawings and Papers 1909-1961
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Rose Greely Architectural Drawings and Papers 1909-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10772
There are 1467 items in this collection (3 Holinger boxes and 14 oversize folders, ca. 5 linear feet). Among these items are 657 architectural drawings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Rose Greely (1883-1961) was born in Washington, D.C., to the Army officer and Arctic explorer, General Adolphus W. Greely, and Henrietta H.C. Nesmith Greely. She studied a variety of art forms at several institutions, such as the Maryland Agricultural College; the Art Institute of Chicago (interior decorating); metal work in Washington, D.C.; and a year's study of silver repousse work and enamelling on metal in Florence, Italy, before she decided to combine her enthusiasm for design and horticulture in a degree in landscape architecture. She attended the Smith College Graduate School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture for Women in Cambridge, Massachusetts (then known as the Cambridge School of Domestic and Landscape Architecture) under the direction of Henry A. Frost, a professor in the Harvard Architecture School and graduated in [1920?].
Upon graduation, Greely worked for Fletcher Steele, a landscape architect in Boston, and was on the staff of the magazine House Beautiful for a year before returning to Washington, D.C.. There she worked as a draftsman for Horace W. Peaslee, concentrating on landscaping problems.
Greely entered into her own practice in 1925 and worked on many different types of projects, including many Washington homes, the grounds of Army Posts, schools, real estate developments, government housing projects, outdoor theaters, playgrounds, roads, gardens, country estates, New England farms, and a garden in Mexico. Most of the drawings in this collection are of private residences and estates, which are listed by the name of the owner or institution. Greely was also the only woman to work on the Advisory Committee of the Williamsburg, Virginia, Restoration Project. Much of the above information was derived from an article "Rose Greely, L.A." in Home Acres Edition Garden Digest(1941 January).
Scope and Content Information
The first series of this collection consists of the architectural drawings by Rose Greely for various residences, estates, and gardens. For a detailed description of each separate sheet see the inventory in Box 2. Each drawing with a Greely number noted in the folder listing can be located in the inventory under that number. The drawings are also listed alphabetically by the name of the owner or institution in the appendix at the end of the guide. The appendix to the guide lists owner, the drawing's Greely inventory number, and all of the folder numbers containing drawings rendered for that owner. Since the drawings for the same residence may be in different sizes, they may be in as many as three separate folders. Please consult the appendix on pages 16-19 of this guide for a list of all folders containing each individual clients drawings.
The second series contains client files kept by Rose Greely which are chiefly concerned with residences in Washington, D.C., Maryland, Virginia, Vermont, New Mexico, and Georgia. Other files include those for the Garden Club of America, the National Rock Garden in Rock Creek Park, The Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia, Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium, the Potomac Rose Garden, and the Williamsburg, Virginia, Restoration Project. Not all clients whose drawings are present in the collection are represented by a file.
Miscellaneous papers comprise the third series and include: articles and talks by Rose Greely; some biographical information concerning Greely; a client list, notes, and inventory of Rose Greely drawings compiled by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library; the correspondence of Rose Greely; correspondence of the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library concerning the Rose Greely Collection; printed matter concerning garden tours; examples of gates, walls, drives, etc.; photographs of the Greely cabin in New Hampshire, Italian Architecture, the Rebsamen estate, Little Rock, Arkansas, and Tudor Place, Washington, D.C.; a thesis by Rose Greely entitled, "Report on a Proposed Cooperative Farm Community" (1920); and a sketchbook belonging to Greely.
Alphabetical List of Clients with folder numbers
CLIENT / GREELY # / FOLDER NUMBERS
Bard / 67 / 6
Barnes / 53 / 13
Bernstein / 9 / 1, 4, 12
Biddle / 62 / 13
Bogan / 36 / 5
Bolton / 55 / 2, 13
Bradford / 32 / 7
Bradley / 66 / 4
Brady / 35 / 12
Bruce / ? / 6, 10
Buchanan / 49 / 1, 4, 13
Burden / 45 / 2, 9
Cafritz / 50 / 1, 13
Child's Playhouse & Garden / ? / 2
Coffey / 72 / 2
Commanding Officers' Quarters / 44 / 5
Connor / 8 / 1, 12
Cosmos Club / 7 / 4, 11
Covington / 21, 33 / 1, 11
Cushman / ? / 8
Decker / 5 / 2
Duer, Beverley / 18 / 4, 12
Duer, Lucie / 12 / 12
Eddy / 14 / 2
Edmonston / 56 / 13
Erwin / 11 / 12
Eustis / 39 / 4, 9
Evermay / ? / 8
Fletcher / 37 / 9
Folger / 52 / 2, 13
Ford / 17 / 1, 12
Gawne / 73 / 5
Gignoux / ? / 8
Gore / 60 / 1, 10
Hahm / 22 / 4, 9
Hale / 38 / 9
Harkness / 69 / 5
Hauge / ? / 1
Hearst / 64 / 5
Herron / ? / 10
"Hillcrest" / ? / 8
Horgan / ? / 8
Iron & Grillwork Examples / ? / 2
Jeffries / ? / 10
Kennedy / 16 / 7
Kienle / 25 / 7, 11
Lanahan / 58 / 5
Lawrence / 24 / 6, 11
Le Clair / 61 / 5
Lodge / 63 / 5
Luttrell / ? / 9
McCormick / 42 / 4, 9
McLean, Mrs. / 68 / 1
McLean, Admiral / 34 / 7
Madeira School / 27 / 12
Magnuson / 26 / 6, 11
Mallon / ? / 10
Mason / 28 / 12
Masonic Memorial Garden / 31 / 7
Montgomery / 3, 20 / 11
Morley / 70 / 13
Morris / 71 / 5
Murray / 54 / 2, 10
Myers / 65 / 11
National Memorial Park / 31 / 12
Parker / 30 / 7, 10
Paull / 23 / 6, 9
Pawley / 1 / 6, 11
Place de la Liberte, Brussels / ? / 5
Potomac Rose Garden / ? / 10
Purdy / 10 / 2, 12
Rebsamen / 19 / 4, 12
Riggs / ? / 2
Rock Creek Park / ? / 9
St. Timothy's School / 48 / 1, 13
Saul / 4 / 11
Schley / 29 / 4, 12
Schwartz / 6 / 7, 11
Shomo / 40 / 5
Simms / 57, 59 / 14
Simpson / ? / 3
Stead / 13 / 2
Strong / 2 / 6, 11
Taylor / ? / 3, 10
Tyssowski / 51 / 4, 13
Vandergrift / 46 / 5, 9
Van Emon / ? / 8
Walker / 15, 41 / 4, 5, 9
Washington Cathedral Garden / ? / 8
Wheeler / 43 / 5
Williams / 47 / 1
Contents List
- SERIES I: ARCHITECTURAL DRAWINGS
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. #9) 1952, 4 sheets (Folder 1)
  - (Folder 1)
  - Buchanan, The Honorable & Mrs. Wiley, 4220 Nebraska Avenue, N.W. Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 49) 1955, 9 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Cafritz, Morris, 2301 Foxhall Road (Gr. # 50) 1937-1938, 14 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Connor, General & Mrs. William D., 2412 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 8) 1948, 2 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Covington, Mrs. J. Harry, 2320 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 33) 1936, 1940, 1947-9, 5 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Ford, Mrs. Sherman, 29 Kalorama Circle, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 17) 1944, 2 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Gore, Miss Mary, River Road, Potomac, Maryland, Swimming Pool Area (Gr. # 60) 1950-1951, 5 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Hauge, Mrs. Gabriel, 3500 Lowell Street, Washington, D.C. 1953, 2 sheets (Folder 1)
  - McLean, Mrs., Pool (Gr. #68) 1925, 2 sheets (Folder 1)
  - St. Timothy's School, Miss Watkin's Garden, Stevenson, Maryland, (Gr. # 48) 1952-1958, 19 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Williams, Mr. & Mrs. R.W., Baltimore, Maryland, (Gr. # 47) 1946, 1948 (Folder 1)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C., 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C., Study "A", (Gr. # 55) 1947 (Folder 2)
  - Burden, Mr. William A.M., 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C., Swimming Pool (Gr. # 45) n.d., 5 sheets (Folder 2)
  - "A Child's Playhouse and Garden" n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Coffey, Dr. & Mrs. Robert J., 4936 Loughboro Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 72) 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Decker, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel J., 2700 Chesapeake Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 5) 1954, 5 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Eddy, Miss Ruth, Old Bennington, Vermont, (Gr. # 14) (Folder 2)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C., 2991 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 52) 1942-3, 1951-1955, 21 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Iron & Grillwork Examples, (Barker, Lansing, Wanamaker) 1926, n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Murray, Mr. & Mrs. Lewis N., Dunkirk, New York, Gardner's House, (Gr. # 54) n.d., 5 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Purdy, James H., 2818 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 10) n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Riggs, Admiral & Mrs. Ralph, Rockville, Maryland 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Stead, Mrs. Dorothy, 3216 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 13) 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Simpson, Mr. & Mrs. Lester C., Marlan Forest, Alexandria, Virginia 1951-1953, 4 sheets (Folder 3)
  - Stead, Mrs. Dorothy, 3216 "O" Street, Washington, D.C. 1936-1937, 63 sheets (Folder 3)
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C., Terrace & Azalea Garden, (Gr. # 9) 1952-1953 (Folder 4)
  - Bradley, Mr. & Mrs. Fontaine, 1820 45 th Street, Washington, D.C., Garden Terrace and Pool, (Gr. # 66) 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Buchanan, The Honorable & Mrs. Wiley, 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 49) 1955, 11 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., Ground Floor Plan, (Gr. # 7) 1941, 4 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Duer, Mr. & Mrs. Beverley, Leesburg, Virginia, (Gr. # 18) 1947-1949, 3 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick, Warrenton, Virginia, Swimming Pool Area, (Gr. # 39) 1946, 2 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Hahm, Emma T., 6036 Daniels Road, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 22) 1926-7, 1938, 5 sheets (Folder 4)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Medill, Washington, D.C., Bowling Green & Playhouse Area, (Gr. # 42) 1929-1931, 4 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Rebsamen, Raymond, Topographic Map of the Property, 2500 North Jackson Street, Little Rock, Arkansas, (Gr. # 19) 1949, 2 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Schley, General & Mrs. Julian, 2815 Dumbarton Street, Washington, D.C., Rails from Potomac Iron Works, (Gr. # 29) 1953, 2 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Tyssowski, Col. & Mrs. John, Cobbler Mountain Farms, Delaplane, Virginia, General Design & Topographic Surveys, (Gr. # 51) 1947, 3 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Walker, Mrs. Albert, Sea Island, Georgia, Planting Plan, (Gr. # 15) 1950-1952, 13 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Bogan, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, 3115 Cleveland Avenue, Washington, D.C., General Design Plan, (Gr. # 36) 1953-1955, 8 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Commanding Officers Quarters- Aberdeen Proving Grounds, Maryland, Study of Planting, (Gr. # 44) 1934, 3 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Gawne, Mrs. J.O., 2439 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Harkness, Mr. & Mrs. Richard, 3035 Dumbarton Avenue, Washington, D.C., Pergola, (Gr. # 69) 1947, 2 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Hearst, Mr. & Mrs. William R., Jr., 2202 Decatur Place, Washington, D.C., Plan for the Gardens, (Gr. # 64) 1948 (Folder 5)
  - Lanahan, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel, 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C., Garden Pool, (Gr. # 58) 1955, 4 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Le Clair, Col. & Mrs. H.P., Friendship, Maryland, General Design Plan for the Grounds (Gr. # 61) 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Lodge, Senator & Mrs., 3132 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., Construction Plan (Gr. # 63) 1948 (Folder 5)
  - Morris, Mr. & Mrs. George M. Morris, Kalorama Road, Washington, D.C., General Design Plan, (Gr. # 71) 1935 (Folder 5)
  - Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium, Memorial to King Albert 1938, 6 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Shomo, Mr. & Mrs. Leslie C., Alexandria, Virginia, General Design, (Gr. # 40) 1952, 1955, 3 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Shomo, Mr. & Mrs. Lester, 631 Oakland Terrace, Alexandria, Virginia, Planting & Construction Plan (Gr. # 40) 1955, 7 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Vandergrift, General & Mrs. A.A., Commandant's House, Marine Barracks, Washington, D.C., Design & Planting Plan, (Gr. # 46) 1944, 6 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Walker, Mrs. Albert W., Westmoreland Hills, Maryland, General Design Plan, (Gr. # 41) 1951, 3 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Wheeler, Mr. & Mrs. George, 2510 Foxhall Road, Washington, D.C., Construction Plan, (Gr. # 43) 1951, 5 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Bard, Mrs. Philip, Hurstleigh, 6 Meadow Road, Baltimore County, Maryland, Terrace & Rose Garden, (Gr. # 67) 1951-1954, 9 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David, 1411 34 th Street, Washington, D.C. 1955, 9 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Garden Seat, # 2 n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Lawrence, Mr. & Mrs. John, "Hartwood," Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania, (Gr. # 24) 1939, 2 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Magnuson, Mrs. Paul, 3121 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 26) 1948-1949, 3 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Paull, Mrs. Singleton, Wheeling, West Virginia, (Gr. # 23) 1952, 6 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Pawley, Mrs. William, "Belvoir," The Plains, Virginia, (Gr. # 1) 1951-1953, 7 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Strong, Mrs. L. Corrin, Washington, D.C. and Gibson Island, Maryland, (Gr. # 2) 1942-3, 1946, 1953-5, 11 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Bradford, Mr. & Mrs. William, Langley Farms, McLean, Fairfax County, Virginia, (Gr. # 32) 1946-1947, 3 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, Gordon, 2915 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 16) 1946, 3 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, Clay Point, Milton, Vermont, (Gr. # 25) 1947-1948, 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - McLean, Admiral Ridley, Grounds of the Army, Navy, & Marine Corps Country Club Grounds, Arlington County, Virginia, (Gr. # 34) 1930, 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Masonic Memorial Garden, National Memorial Park, Falls Church, Virginia, (Gr. # 31) 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Parker, Mrs. Andrew, 4000 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 30) 1954, 7 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Schwartz, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel T., 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 6) 1938-1955, 30 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Cushman, E.S., Shaftsbury, Vermont, Topography 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Evermay Service Court Gate Lantern 1934, 2 sheets (Folder 8)
  - Gignoux, damaged torn sheet n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "Hillcrest" Wading Pool n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Horgan, Dr. Edmund, Topographical Map of the Estate, Delaplane, Virginia 1929 (Folder 8)
  - Van Emon, Mrs. C.G., Topographical Survey, Barnesville, Montgomery County, Maryland 1941 (Folder 8)
  - W.C. & A.N. Miller Developing Company Jobs # A-162, Loughboro Road, 11 sheets and # A-175, Van Ness Street 1959, 7 sheets (Folder 8)
  - Washington Cathedral Garden 1926-1927, 2 sheets (Folder 8)
  - Topographical Survey, Lot 159, 34 th and "O" Streets 1955 (Folder 8)
  - Burden, William A.M., 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 45) n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick, "Bellevue," Warrenton, Virginia (Gr. # 39) 1946-1947, 10 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Fletcher, Colonel & Mrs. Robert H., Leesburg, Virginia (Gr. # 37) 1937-1938, 5 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Hahm, Miss Emma T., 6036 Daniels Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 22) n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Hale, Mrs. Chandler (Gr. # 38) 1934-1935, 3 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Luttrell, Mrs. A. Lothrop, Bethesda, Montgomery County, Maryland 1940, 2 sheets (Folder 9)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Medill, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 42) 1929-1931, 8 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Paull, Mary V., "Shawnee Hills," Wheeling, West Virginia (Gr. # 23) 1952, 4 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Rock Creek Park, Washington, D.C. 1932, 7 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Vandergrift, General & Mrs., Commandant's House, Marine Barracks, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 46) 1944 (Folder 9)
  - Walker, Mr. & Mrs. Albert Walker, Sea Island, Georgia, (Gr. # 15) 3 sheets, and Westmoreland Hills, Montgomery County, Maryland, (Gr. # 41) 1949-1951, 2 sheets (Folder 9)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David Bruce, New Windsor, Carroll County, Maryland 1956, 6 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Gore, Mary, "Marwood Estate," River Road, Montgomery County, Maryland, (Gr. # 60) 1950, 3 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Herron, General & Mrs. Charles Douglas, Cemetery Lot Bench and Marker 1948 (Folder 10)
  - Jeffries, L.E., "Muckross Estate," Fairfax County, Virginia 1929 (Folder 10)
  - Mallon, Mr. & Mrs. Paul, "Belle Haven," Virginia 1939-1940, 2 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Murray, Mr. & Mrs. Lewis N., "Dunkeld," Dunkirk, New York (Gr. # 54) 1932 (Folder 10)
  - Parker, Andrew, 4000 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., Garden and Wall Panel, (Gr. # 30) 1943-1944, 2 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Potomac Rose Garden, West Potomac Park, Washington, D.C. 1945 (Folder 10)
  - Taylor, William H., 28th & Q Streets, Washington, D.C. 1937, 15 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Cosmos Club Garden Design, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 7) 1941, 2 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Covington, Mr. & Mrs. J. Harry, Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 33) and "Minden Cottage," Craftsbury Common, Vermont (Gr. # 21) 1934-1937, 5 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, Clay Point, Milton, Vermont (Gr. # 25) 1948, 3 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Lawrence, Mr. & Mrs. John W., "Hartwood," Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania (Gr. # 24) 1938-1939, 4 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Magnuson, Mrs. Paul, 3121 "O" Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 26) 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Montgomery, Mr. & Mrs. William, "Blythe Knoll," 6200 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 20) and (Gr. # 3) 1936-1950, 8 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Myers, Mr. & Mrs. George Hewitt, 2310 "S" Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 65) 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Pawley, Mrs. William, "Belvoir," The Plains, Virginia, (Gr. # 1) 1952-1953, 3 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Saul, Mr. & Mrs. Andrew, 3035 Chainbridge Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 4) 1941, 4 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Schwartz, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel T., 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 6) 1938-1939, 1953, 2 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Strong, L. Corrin, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 2) n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 9) 1952-1953, 2 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Brady, Mrs. James C., Jr., The Gardens at Mill House, Far Hills, New Jersey (Gr. # 35) 1933-1934, 5 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Connor, General & Mrs. William, 2412 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 8) 1941, 2 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Duer, Mr. & Mrs. Beverley, "Woodburn," Leesburg, Virginia (Gr. # 18) 1946-1949, 4 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Duer, Miss Lucie, Warrenton, Virginia (Gr. # 12) 1948-1949, 2 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Erwin, Mrs. Henry D., "Arbremont" Perennial Garden (Gr. # 11) 1935 (Folder 12)
  - Ford, Mrs. Sherman, Twenty-nine, Kalorama Circle, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 17) 1944 (Folder 12)
  - Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia (Gr. # 27) 1933, 1936, 3 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Mason, Rosa Tucker, "Col Alto," Lexington, Virginia (Gr. # 28) 1937, 1940-1, 6 sheets (Folder 12)
  - National Memorial Park, Falls Church, Virginia (Gr. # 31) 1939, 6 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Purdy, Mr. & Mrs. James H., Jr., 2618 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 10) 1947, 5 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Rebsamen, Mr. & Mrs. Raymond, 2500 North Jackson Street, Little Rock, Arkansas (Gr. # 19) 1949-1951, 10 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Schley, General & Mrs. Julian, 2815 Dumbarton Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 29) 1949, 2 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Barnes, Mr. & Mrs. James M., "Montevideo" (Gr. # 53) 1947-1950, 3 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Biddle, Mr. & Mrs. Francis, 1669 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 62) 1947-1949 (Folder 13)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C., 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 55) 1947, 6 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Buchanan, Honorable & Mrs. Wiley T., 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 49) 1955-1956, 8 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Cafritz, Mr. & Mrs. Morris, 2301 Foxhall Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 50) 1937-1938, 15 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Edmonston, Mrs. E.D., 2414 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 56) 2 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C., 2991 Woodland Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 52) 1942-1951, 12 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Morley, Mr. & Mrs. Felix (Gr. # 70) 1934 (Folder 13)
  - St. Timothy's School, Stevenson, Maryland (Gr. # 48) 1952-1953, 4 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Tyssowski, Colonel & Mrs. John, "Cobbler Mountain Farms," Delaplane, Virginia (Gr. # 51) 1947 (Folder 13)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G., "Los Poblamos Ranch," Albuquerque, New Mexico (Gr. # 57) 1932-1934, 43 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G., Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 59) 1932, 3 sheets (Folder 14)
- SERIES II: CLIENT FILES
  - Bard, Mrs. Philip: Baltimore County, Maryland 1953-1956 (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Leo M.: 2420 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. 1951-1953, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C.: 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. 1947 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David: 1411 34th Street, Washington, D.C. 1955-1956, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David: Farm at New Windsor, Carroll County, Maryland 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Buchanan, Wiley: 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick: Warrenton, Virginia 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C.: 2991 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 1)
  - Garden Club of America: National Rock Garden in Rock Creek Park 1932 (Box 1)
  - Greely, Rose: Garden 1938-1965 (Box 1)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene: "Clay Point," Milton, Vermont 1948 (Box 1)
  - The Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia 1945 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Clients 1945-1960 (Box 1)
  - Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium 1944-1946 (Box 1)
  - Potomac Rose Garden 1952 (Box 1)
  - Schwartz, Samuel T.: 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. 1948-1955 (Box 1)
  - Shomo, Lester: 631 Oakland Terrace, Alexandria, Virginia 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G.: Los Poblamos Ranch, Albuquerque, New Mexico 1932-1934, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Simpson, Mr. & Mrs. Lester: Marlan Forest, Alexandria, Virginia 1951 (Box 1)
  - Strong, Mrs. L. Corrin: Washington, D.C./Gibson Island, Maryland 1943 (Box 1)
  - Taylor, William H.: Residence and Carriage House at Q and 28th Street n.d. (Box 1)
  - Walker, Albert W.: Sea Island, Georgia 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Williamsburg Committee of the American Society of Landscape Architects 1929-1930, 1941 (Box 1)
- SERIES III: MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - Articles featuring gardens designed by Rose Greely 1937-1954, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Articles by Rose Greely - Published 1922-1961 (Box 2)
  - Articles by Rose Greely - Unpublished 1933-1936, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Biographical & Professional Information re Rose Greely 1909-1946 (Box 2)
  - Client List of Rose Greely compiled by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library re the Rose Greely Collection 1981-1985, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of Rose Greely 1926-1954 (Box 2)
  - Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library Notes re Rose Greely n.d. (Box 2)
  - Garden Tours 1929-1940, 1950, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Gates, Walls, Drives, etc.: Notes and Other Material ca. 1936-1954 (Box 2)
  - Inventory of the Rose Greely Architectural Drawings made by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library [ca. 1984?] (Box 2)
  - Photographs of the Greely Cabin in New Hampshire 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Italian Architecture n.d. (Box 3)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous [ca. 1949-1951 ?], n.d. (Box 3)
  - "Report on a Proposed Cooperative Farm Community" - Thesis in the School of Domestic Architecture and Landscape Architecture, Cambridge, Massachusetts 1920, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Sketchbook belonging to Rose Greely n.d. (Box 3)
  - Talks by Rose Greely 1934, 1945, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Travel Data 1932, 1956-1957 (Box 3)